(水月)ひとつ聞いてもいいかな。
(サスケ)なんだ？
Can I ask you something?
What is it?
Why are you gathering men?
どうして 仲間を集めるの？
オレには目的がある。
I have a goal...
その目的に近づくには
小隊のほうが効率がいい。
And I have a better chance of
achieving it with a small platoon.
大蛇丸に近づいたときから➡
Ever since I approached Orochimaru,
this moment is all I've thought about,
こうなったときのことを考え➡
力のある忍を
前もって選抜しておいた。
and I've been pre-selecting
highly skilled Ninja.
へえ。
Oh...?
けど だったら 香燐を
選ぶことはないと思うけどね。
So... why would you choose Karin?
アイツは ボクと違って
大蛇丸の部下だよ。
Unlike me,
she's a follower of Orochimaru...
The warden of the southern hideout
大蛇丸に狩り集められた実験体を
ぶち込んだ➡
where Orochimaru kept
his test subjects locked up.
南のアジトの看守殿だ。
それに
大蛇丸の命令だとか言って➡
After claiming to be
under Orochimaru's orders,
she tinkered with
my body countless times.
アイツには 何度も
体をいじくられたよ。
Besides, her personality turns me off.
第一
あの性格が好きになれない。
確かに 扱いやすそうな強い忍は
他にいくらでもいた。
Granted, there were other strong Ninja
I could have swayed.
But she has a special power
no one else possesses.
しかし ヤツは他にない
特別な能力を持っている。
Well... I'll admit that.
まあ それは認めるけどね。
A nice smell... and a bad odor.
(香燐)いい香り。
それと イヤなにおい。
There's hardly any security
in this hideout.
ずいぶんと警備が手薄なアジトだね。
They should at least build a fence.
塀くらい建てればいいのに。
She has this place under control.
There's no need.
アイツがここをおさめているんだ
必要ないだろう。
Still, it's too quiet.
にしても静かすぎないかな。
You'd think that word of
Orochimaru's death
大蛇丸が死んだという
ウワサが届いていても➡
had already reached this place...
おかしくないのにさ。
え？
キミだって持ってるっしょ。
You have one too.
That one is more suitable.
そっちのほうがあってる。
Open up!
開けゴマ！
Say, I've been thinking.
なあやっぱり オレは思うんだよ
あの噂は 本当だったんじゃ？
That rumor must be true--
Shut up!
やめろ！ そいつを口にした者が
どうなってきたか…。
You know what happened to
the others who brought that up...
ああ そうだな。
Yeah...
you're right...
Oh, damn it...
まずい まずい！
あれは うちはサスケだ！
That's Uchiha Sasuke!
どうして こんなところへ？
What's he doing in a place like this?
It's been quite a while
since he came here with Orochimaru.
もう ずいぶん前になるぜ
大蛇丸と ヤツが来たのは。
そうだよ なんで大蛇丸と来ない？
Yeah, why didn't he come
with Orochimaru?
He's with a guy
we've never seen before...
あんな見たこともねえヤツと…。
あの噂は 本当かもしれんぞ！
Maybe that rumor is true...!
About Orochimaru being dead.
大蛇丸が死んだって！
That's it!
Sasuke must've killed Orochimaru!
そうか サスケが大蛇丸を
倒したんだよ！
And he's come to free us all!
それで オレたちを
解放しに来てくれたんだぜ！
バーカ そんなこと
あるわけねえだろ。
Idiot. Like that'll ever happen!
だいたい 大蛇丸が
やられるわけがない。
Besides, Orochimaru would
never get killed.
(香燐)やっぱり アンタか サスケ。
So it's you, after all... Sasuke.
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
the "impulses" that makes you want to meet it
aitaku naru no shoudou
the "innocence" that makes you want to cry
nakitaku naru no junjou
they've gone into the summer fire
natsu no hi ni tobikonda
the fireflies aren't coming back
hotaru wa kaeranai
you didn't say a single word and left a kiss for me behind
anata wa nanimo iwazu kuchizuke wo nokoshite
and nodded as you still got burned
kitsuzuku mama unazuita ne
it was so sad that my life was wavering
kanashii hodo inochi yurameiteita
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
sha la la my sweet lovely dear
sha la la itoshiki hito
I can also see you right now
anata mo mieteiru no
the dazzling moon will softly
mabayui tsuki ga sotto
illuminate the morning day
ashita wo terashite
and strongly and strongly shine on
tsuyoku tsuyoku kagayaite
Guardian of the
Iron Wall
サスケ アンタがここへ
１人で来たってことは➡
Sasuke...
The fact that you're here alone
must mean that the rumors were true.
あの噂は 本当だったみたいだな。
ひどいな ボクもいるってのに。
Geez, that's mean. I'm here too.
で ここに何の用だ？
And? What brings you here?
サスケが キミに話があるんだってさ。
Sasuke has something
to discuss with you.
立ち話もなんだから
別部屋に案内してくれないかな？
We can't stand out here and talk,
so take us inside, will you?
久しぶりに歩いたら
ヘトヘトでね。
It's been so long since I've walked...
I'm exhausted.
なんだよ 話って。
What do you want to talk about?
だから 立ち話もなんだからって
言ってるんだけどね 香燐。
I said let's not stand out here, Karin.
ボクは キミの眼中にないってことは
わかってるけどさ。
Although I know
you're totally ignoring me.
フン！
Humph!
イヤな感じ。
何言ってんの お前？
You disgust me.
What'd you say?
いいかげんにしろ 香燐。
部屋に案内しろ。
Cut it out, Karin. Take us inside.
わかったわよ。
Fine.
香燐 ついてこい
お前が必要だ。
Karin, follow me. I need you.
はあ？ なんで お前なんかに？
Huh?! Why would I follow you?
I'm under orders to oversee this place!
ウチは ここを任されてんだよ。
大蛇丸は もういない。
Orochimaru is already gone.
捕まえてるヤツらは
どうすんだよ。
What about the prisoners here?
そういやさ アイツらずいぶんと
おとなしかったね。
Speaking of prisoners,
they were awfully quiet.
大蛇丸が死んだって噂
このアジトにも届いてたろ？
Have the rumors about
Orochimaru's death reached them?
前に ここに来たときよりも
囚人の数が微妙に減ってる。
The number of prisoners has slightly
lessened since I came here last.
それと入り口前の庭に➡
Also, there are signs of recent digging
in the grounds in front of the entrance.
最近 穴でも掘ったような
形跡がいくつかあった。
香燐 お前の頭脳をもってすれば➡
Karin, with that sharp intellect,
information control must be your forte.
情報統制などお手の物だろ。
そっか 大蛇丸が死んだという
ウワサが囚人たちに流れ➡
I get it.
Rumors about Orochimaru's death
began spreading among the prisoners,
暴動に発展しないように香燐が
うまく立ち回っていた。
so in order to avoid a riot,
Karin has been wisely taking action...
ということか。
Is that it?
おい あのウワサ知ってるか？
Hey, do you know about
that rumor?
ああ 知ってる知ってる。
大蛇丸が 死んだって話だろ。
Yeah, I know.
About Orochimaru being killed, right?
ああ。
Yeah.
(水月)檻の中にスパイを紛れ込ませ➡
You planted a spy among the inmates
ちょっとでも大蛇丸の
ウワサをするものがいれば…。
and if anyone began gossiping
about Orochimaru...
香燐 お前のその慎重さが➡
Karin, it's your cautious nature which
maintained order in the prison.
このアジトの秩序を保った。
というより お前自身を救った。
Or rather... kept you alive.
嫌な言い方するんじゃないよ！
You'd better stop talking like that!
さすが大蛇丸仕込みの女だ。
You've been trained by Orochimaru,
all right. Man, you're scary.
こええ。 オレたちが来たことも
とっくに感づいてたんだろうな。
You probably sensed
our presence long ago.
下手すれば 殺されてたかも
しれないってことだ。
You could've even killed us by now.
アンタ１人だったらね。
If you were alone.
サスケだったらいいってのかよ。
But not Sasuke?
そんなこと 言ってない。
サスケはいわば同僚だ。
I didn't say that!
Sasuke is a colleague.
それに
ウワサの真偽を確かめたかった。
I wanted to see if
the rumors were true...
サスケが大蛇丸を
やったっていうウワサをね。
that Sasuke killed Orochimaru.
オレがやった。
何簡単に言ってんだよ！
I did kill him.
How can you say that so casually?!
水月 このアジトに捕らえられてる
ヤツらを 全員解放しろ。
Suigetsu... Release everyone
who is held prisoner here.
な…。
はぁ～。
Wha--?!
Geez... You always
order people around.
《相変わらず命令口調だな》
勝手なことすんじゃねえよ！
You can't just come here
and take over!
私がどんだけ
苦労してここをしめてきたか。
You don't know what it took
to keep things in order here...
囚人がいなけりゃ
監視役も必要なくなるわけだ。
Without prisoners,
there won't be any need for a warden.
もう一度言う。
オレについて来い 香燐。
I'll say it once more.
Come with me, Karin.
どうする？
What'll you do?
じゃあ 囚人たちを
解放しに行って来る。
Well, anyway,
I'll go and release the prisoners.
お断りだね！ だいたい
アンタについて行く義理はないだろ。
I refuse! Besides...
I'm under no obligation to follow you!
ふ～ん。
仕方ない。
お前がそこまで嫌がるのなら➡
Too bad...
Since you seem dead set against it,
I'll just ask someone else.
他を当たろう。
やっぱりだぜ！ うちはサスケが
大蛇丸を倒したというのは。
I knew it!
The rumors that Uchiha Sasuke
brought down Orochimaru were true!
ホントだったのか。
ああ そうだよ。
Yeah, it's true.
捕まってるオレたちは どうなる？
What'll happen to those of us in here?
もちろん自由だよ。
Of course, you're free to go.
ホ ホントか？
A-Are you sure?!
ああ。 ボクだって同じ
捕らわれの身だった。
Yeah... I was once imprisoned too.
But as you can see, I'm free.
でも こうして外にいるだろ。
今からカギを開けるよ。
I'm going to unlock the cells.
Before that, I have one favor to ask.
ただ その前に➡
みんなに
ひとつだけお願いがあるんだ。
何だ!? 何でも言ってくれ！
What is it?! Ask us anything!
そうだな…。 大蛇丸を倒し➡
Well...
The one who defeated Orochimaru
and gave us our freedom is Sasuke.
ボクたちの自由を
取り戻してくれたのはサスケだ。
外に出たら そのことを
言い広めてくれ。
When you're out,
spread the word to everyone...
この世に
安定と平和をもたらす男が➡
A man has appeared who will
bring peace and tranquility to this world.
現れたとね。
行く！
I'm coming.
あっ…。
サスケがぁ
どうしてもって言うなら➡
Since you're so adamant...
ついてってやるよ！
I'll go with you.
どういうことだ？
What's this?
That was a quick change of heart.
心変わりが早いな。
よく考えたらぁ➡
見張りも
あきちゃってたところだし。
After thinking it over,
I realized I'm tired of
guarding this place.
(水月)なかからカギを… あの女。
It's locked from the inside...
That woman!
フンッ！
水月か…。
邪魔者はほっといて！
That's Suigetsu.
Let's forget about that nuisance,
okay, Sasuke?
ねっ サスケ。
お前 少しはなれろ。
You... Don't get so close.
ねぇ どうせなら
ウチとサスケだけでいいんじゃない？
Look... what's wrong with
just you and me?
水月なんていらないだろ あれ。
We don't need a guy like... Suigetsu.
お前のその小ズルさと用心深さ➡
Your cunning and sense of caution...
そして何より
そのチャクラを感じる能力。
and especially your power
to sense Chakra...
お前は使えるとわかっていた。
From the moment I met you,
I knew I could use you.
初めて会ったあのときから。
《そう… あのとき…》
Yes... that time...
((大蛇丸様から言われて来た。
Orochimaru-sama sent me here.
To assist you, Uchiha Sasuke.
うちはサスケ アンタを手伝えと。
２時間前にアジトから
118名の実験体が脱走した。
Two hours ago, 118 test subjects
escaped from the hideout.
時間的にみて
全員 まだこの森のなかにいる。
Judging from the time,
they are all still in this forest.
捕獲命令は
生死を問わずと聞いている。
I understand that this order
is to capture them dead or alive.
ああ。
だったら とっとと始めるよ。
Yeah.
Well then, let's begin.
《50… 60…。
50, 60...
70… 80… 90… 100》
70...80...90...100!
見つけた。
Found them!
まずは
近場で潜んでるヤツから いくよ。
I'll start with the ones hiding
closest to us.
後方50メートルに １人。
前方10時の方向に ４人。
There's one fifty meters behind us.
And four more in front of us
at ten o'clock.
早い！
So fast!
ついてこられるか？
任務だからな。
Can you keep up?
香燐 オレの目となれ。
It's my duty.
Karin, become my eyes.
うっ… ウチに命令するな！
D-Don't give me orders!
１時半の方向に潜んでるのが３人。
Three are hiding over at 1:30.
さらに そこから
９時の方向に待ち伏せ５人。
And from that point, at nine o'clock,
there are five more waiting
to ambush us.
うっ…。
何人だ？
これで 84。
How many?
サスケ どうして殺さない？
This one makes 84.
Sasuke, why don't you kill them?
お前 ぬるいな。
You're so lenient.
オレが殺したいのは
たったひとりだけだ。
There's only one man
I have a desire to kill.
《うっ… 何？
コイツの… このチャクラ…》
Wh-What...?!
This guy's... Chakra...!
《コイツ… かっけえ…》
This guy... is cool!
香燐。
Karin!
香燐！
ウチのために… お前…。
You did that... for me?
お前を失えば すべての実験体を
捕らえることは困難になる。
If I were to lose you, capturing
the escapees would become difficult.
わかってる。
I know!
《あのとき…》
At that moment...
《ウチは サスケに… サスケに…》
I... Sasuke... Sasuke, I...
ああ… 刃こぼれしてないかな。
Hope my blade isn't chipped...
さあ いこうよ サスケ。
香燐は ダメだったんだろう？
Let's go, Sasuke.
Karin turned you down, didn't she?
いや どうやら ついてくるようだ。
No. It seems she's coming.
だ… 誰が行くっつった!?
Wh-Who said I'm coming?!
ウチは たま… たまたま
一緒に行方が同じだった。
I just... I just happened to be
going in the same direction.
行くだけ… だけで…。
That's all, nothing else...!
だから… その…。
へえ～ なら ちょうどいいね。
途中まで一緒に行こうよ。
Oh, how nice.
Then we can travel together partway.
ああ… 途中までな。
Yeah, just part of the way!
(水月)さて次は重吾だね。
All right... Next is Jugo.
なに！
重吾のところへ行くだって!?
What? You're going to see Jugo?
途中まで一緒なだけなキミには
関係ないでしょう。
That shouldn't concern you
関係ないけど それがどうした！
やんのか コラ！
since you're just coming
with us part of the way.
Sure, I could care less,
but what's wrong with asking?
行くぞ。
Wanna make something of it,
you jerk?!
あっ… ああ。
Let's go!
Y-Yeah...
行ってやる！
I'll go!
《香燐 : うちはサスケ…
そのクールな顔もいいけれど…》
Uchiha Sasuke...
He always looks so calm and cool...
《この感じ ゾクゾクする…。
This feeling... is exciting.
今まで何百 何千と出会った中で
最高のチャクラ… グッとくる～！
Of the hundreds, the thousands
I've encountered,
his Chakra is the best...
It grabs you!
それに比べて…》
ん？ 何だよ？
Compared with that...
What?!
アンタのチャクラ 苦手だわ。
Your Chakra... bothers me.
あぁ？
ボクのほうこそ！
Huh?
I could say the same about yours.
いや やっぱ女…
やっぱ女がいいな。
No, a woman...
A woman is nice... No, wait.
いや 待てよ。
やっぱ男か… やっぱ男がいいか。
A guy? I guess a guy is better...
いや やっぱ女か…？
No... A woman...?
女が…。
A woman... No...
いや それよりも 男…。
Maybe a guy...
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
life always throws you curveballs and the reason of that is
yo kono yo wa hitosujinawa de ikanai sore wa naze nara
it's a test made by God so that's why it's quite hard
kamisama ga tsukutta tesuto dakara muzukashii nda
arts? science? or rather how about ethics?
bunkei rikei mushiro doutoku kimi nara kore wo dou toku
this is just like life so put your heart and soul into seriousness
kore wa maru de jinsei dakara uchikomu shinken ni
we worry ourselves lose ourselves and we keep asking ourselves questions
bokura wa nayamu mayou nandomo jibun ni toikakeru
we aren't one and relentesly persue our search for answers
hitotsu ja nai kotae sagashi gamushara ni oikakeru
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
the current me would tell me that if I was from the future
mirai no bokura nara ima no boku ni oshiete agerareru
you should keep pursuing it until your efforts change yourself
kimi no doryoku ga jishin ni kawaru toki made oitsuzukereba ii
Next Episode
We have to keep walking?
I'm exhausted.
We're about to go to
the northern hideout.
If you're acting like that, you'll be killed
the moment you arrive there.
I didn't realize the place
is so dangerous.
Yeah, the northern hideout is
no ordinary hideout.
What do you mean by that?
The place is
a human experiment facility.
Intolerably bad monsters were
created there and kept under restraint.
Jugo of the
Northern Hideout
Next time: "Jugo of the Northern Hideout"
(ナルト)うずまきナルトの
『ぐるぐるラジオ』！
本日のゲストは！
Uzumaki Naruto's Swirling Radio!
Our guest today is...
(カカシ)どうも！ はたけカカシです。
それでは さっそく。
Hello, I'm Hatake Kakashi.
リハのときさ 勝手なアドリブ入れるの
ホント やめてくんねえかな。
Getting right to the point,
can you stop ad-libbing
during rehearsals?
な… なんだと!? オレは
現場の空気を和ませようとだな！
What? I'm just trying to
keep everyone calm.
そのわりには 楽しそうだよな。
そ… そういう演技をしてるんだ。
Well, you sure seem to enjoy it.
へぇ～ まあ いいや。
Th-That's just an act!
ここで お便りを。
ラジオネーム 鳥獣戯画さん。
Oh yeah?
Well, whatever.
Here's a postcard from
"Super Beast Scroll".
「カカシ先生のあだ名を
考えてみたのですが➡
エロハリネズミなんてどうですか？」。
"I've been thinking about
a nickname for Kakashi-sensei."
オレの威厳が…。
"How about Pervy Hedgehog?"
えっと 続いては
ラジオネーム キラキラ乙女さん。
There goes my dignity...
And moving on to "Sparkling Maiden".
「ズバリ 結婚しないんですか？
それと集合時間に遅れてくるクセ
あれ ホント迷惑です。
"I'll get right to the point!
Aren't you going to get married?"
"Also, your habit of always being late
when your team assembles.
あと 私たちの前で
いかがわしい本を読まないで。
That's very rude."
はっきり言って
すっげぇセクハラです」。
"Finally, please don't read
your smut books in front of us.
To put it bluntly,
that's sexual harassment."
あれ？ カカシ先生どうしたの？
カカシ先生！ また来てくれるかな？
- Kakashi-sensei?! What's wrong?
- Man...
二度と来るかぁ～！
Kakashi-sensei!
Will you come back again?
I'll never come again!!
(ナツ)この先にいるエルザを倒し➡
俺は Ｓ級魔導士になるんだ！
誰かいるぞ。
(ハッピー)誰だろう？
(２人)あぁ…。